# MICHAELA YOUNG

#### Junior Software Developer

Graduated from an intensive coding bootcamp with a Certificate of Software Development. Built front-end and back-end web applications using full-stack C# .NET, MVC, Node.js, and other frameworks. Strong communication skills, pragmatic yet also a creative thinker, plenty of experience with people in a diversity of settings, comfortable with different cultures, takes the initiative, very task-oriented, and enjoys productivity, organizing, and condensing.

mickee.birti@gmail.com



Stow, Ohio, United States



in linkedin.com/in/michaela-mickee-young



micker7.github.io

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Study Program**

We Can Code It

01/2023 - 04/2023

Cleveland, OH

Course

 Received Certificate of Software Development from Course Report's "Best Coding Bootcamp" 7 years in a row. Completed 14 intensive weeks learning C# and .Net full-stack skills along with other skills listed.

## Study Program

University of Akron

2017 - 2019 Akron, OH

Degree

 Bachelor's Degree of Multidisciplinary Studies in Communication, **Business, Foreign Culture** 

# Study Program

Hocking College

2014 - 2016

**Dearee** 

Associate of Science in Wilderness Horsemanship

Equine Massage and Acupressure Therapy Certificate

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Server

Flury's Cafe

2017 - 2022

Cuyahoga Falls, OH

Nelsonville, OH

Tasks

 Served food/drinks, took dine-in orders and carry-out orders, washed dishes, cashier, seated, bussed, cleaned, food prepped, odd jobs, restocked, answered phone, packaged carry-out orders, opening/closing

# Typist Reviewer

Old Republic Title

2020 - 2022 Akron, OH

Tasks

 Worked out of a queue of orders, verified documentation, incorporated information into computer program called Citrix, created documents, used websites for additional information as needed, edited documents and added information, attended weekly zoom meetings, reviewed compiled information and documentation, used interoffice communication tools, maintained daily productivity, updated documents and orders, completed feedback requests.

## **SKILLS**



#### **PROJECTS**

#### Virtual Pet

- Technologies used: C#, Git, Scrum
- Designed a fun game within a 3-person team over 2 weeks, where the user can create and interact with pets.

#### **Review Website**

- Technologies used: C#, MVC, HTML, CSS, Git, Scrum
- O Designed a website with another classmate within two weeks, where a user can add restaurants and leave reviews to those restaurants.

#### Bunny Maker

- Technologies used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Git
- Designed a clicker game where a user can click to make, sacrifice, or multiply bunnies by click.

#### Pantry Squirrel

- Technologies used: C#, JavaScript, API, MVC, HTML, CSS, Git, Scrum
- Designed a website using a public API where a user can register an account and add ingredients they have in order to obtain recipes that include those specific ingredients from the database. Created over 3 weeks in a group of 5 people.

## **AWARDS**

Italian American Society Award

Dean's List – 6 time recipient

President's List - 2-time recipient

## **INTERESTS**

I enjoy walking everywhere on vacation, reading in a comfy chair, eating all things bread, riding horses fast, longboarding, painting, building lego sets, and going camping with husband, friends, and Siberian husky.

## **ORGANIZATIONS**

Women Who Code (03/2023 - Present)

Memher